WILLIS OPIYO

Software engineer/Designer /accountant/ procurement officer

| +254 704 686 100 | willisopiyo95@gmail.com | Nairobi, Kenya | LinkedIn.com/in/willis-opiyo-7490492a3/ |
|------------------|-------------------------|----------------|---|
| | | | |

ABOUT ME

I am a graduate of Zetech University. I'm very passionate about computers, programming, and article writing. I am a software engineer with 5 years of programming under my belt. I have done a lot of online courses on software engineering and programming as well. I have also taken my time to learn more about accounting through the internet and the majority of Adobe programs such as Dreamweaver, photoshop, lightroom, and Premiere Pro. Most of my video editing jobs I have done through Fiverr and freelancer sites. I have projects that I have done as a sole programmer and others as an assistant as highlighted on my project page. Through my years of multiple different working positions and different areas I have acquired skills that I would get on my days at the university

MY SKILLS-

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS Open-mindedness | Openness to learning | Professionalism | Team Leadership

Excellent Communication | Organization | Problem-Solving skills | integrity

Self-Motivation | Self-confidence | Flexible

TECHNICAL SKILLS Object-oriented Programming | Web development | Networking | Python programming | Node.js |

CCTV operations | Accounts and financial management | Cloud computing | Database management

Client-server management | Computer security | Microsoft Office applications |

Computer management | JavaScript | react.js | CSS

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Infinitech Circle | Nairobi, Kenya | 2020 - 2024

- Design websites for clients
- Help clients with some of the problems on the websites
- Edit out problems that were present on the website which were made by the previous programmer
- Help out a client with cPanel problems
- Set up webmail for clients and help them use it
- Run client's website management on the server level
- Design and create a web application

FREELANCE WEB DEVELOPER

fiverr.com | Kenya | 2017 - 2024

- My work is to take contracts that require me to code a certain part of the website
- Go through codes to see the errors and changes needed

FREELANCE VIDEOGRAPHER

fiver.com | Kenya | 2017 - 2024

- Edit videos by the client's desire
- Caption already edited videos

FREELANCE CONTENT WRITER

fiverr.com | Kenya | 2017 - 2024

- Write a script and edit a script for clients
- Write script for Instagram

• Write a script for YouTube clients

FREELANCE IT CONSULTANT

- Update client computers
- Install windows and Microsoft office

ACCOUNTANT

Icon hotel | Kiambu, Kenya | 2019 - 2024

| Kenya | 2017 - 2024

- Check and keep to date on the sales of the club
- Follow up on the payment of the suppliers
- Pay the employees of the hotel
- Write cheques for suppliers
- Stock-taking

PROCUREMENT OFFICER

Icon Gardens | Kiambu, Kenya | 2019 - 2024

- Purchase liquor for the restaurant
- Check for the lowest cost possible to help us cut losses
- Track orders that we had ordered from suppliers
- Negotiate contracts with companies such as Tony West Limited

IT INTERN

Talent Soko Africa | Kajiado, Kenya | 2020 – 2024

- Manage the app database
- Update and write new code for the app
- Suggested new hires for the organization
- Update on the downloads of the app on Google Play

IT PERSONNEL

Siron medical center | Nairobi, Kenya | 2022 - 2024

- Maintain computers and systems
- Updating database
- Repair broken computer
- Repair CCTV cameras

IT ASSISTANT

Miti gap | Nairobi, Kenya | 2019 - 2024

- Help out in web designing
- Managing client databases
- Design and coding clients web applications

SUPERVISOR

Icon Garden | Kiambu, Kenya | 2019 - 2024

- Write waiters/waitress and staff members shift orders
- Run day-to-day tasks like counter-checking on the muster roll-checking's
- Follow up on customers if the services offered were to their liking and suggestions on what needs improvements
- Hiring and training staff members
- Working with a given budget to meet the required standards

ASSISTANT MANAGER

Icon Garden | Kiambu, Kenya | 2019 - 2024

- Providing the manager with the day-to-day operations and administrative duties
- Answering guests' questions in the absence of the manager
- Hiring and training new staff
- Check on food or drinks being handled are up to standard

DESIGNER

Infinitech Circle | Nairobi, Kenya | 2020 - 2024

Logo design

- Posters and banner design
- Social media content like posters

SOCIAL MEDIA MARKETING

Infinitech Circle | Nairobi, Kenya | 2020 - 2024.

- Posting content
- Designing content
- Answering questions on platforms
- Keeping the social media pages active at all times

SALES PARTNER

cintel core limitless | Nairobi, Kenya | 2023 - 2024

Doing sale of solutions to client

Captain | Eastleigh High School, Nairobi, Kenya

Marketing the company

| SOCIAL MEDIA MARKETING | 20 th Feb 2023 |
|---|--------------------------------|
| Udemy online course | |
| MACHINE LEARNING | 4 th Sep 2023 |
| Codecademy online course | |
| SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 25 th Aug 2022 |
| Udemy online course | |
| PROCUREMENT/ACQUISITION AND CONTRACT MANAGEMENT | 19 th July 2021 |
| Udemy online course | |
| JAVA SCRIPT PROGRAMMING | 28 th Nov 2019 |
| Udemy online course | |
| DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | 13 th Nov 2020 |
| Zetech University, Kiambu, Kenya | |
| VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE | 16th June 2016 |
| Peer Educator I choose life, Nairobi, Kenya | |
| VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE | 13 th June 2023 |
| Facilitator Star of Hope, Juja, Kenya | 13 Julie 2023 |
| racilitator Star or Hope, Juja, Kerrya | |
| LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE | 11 th February 2014 |

ACHIEVEMENTS & VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

PROJECTS

| INFINITECH CIRCLE | 2021 |
|--|------|
| Infinitech circle website Main programmer www.infinitechcircle.com | |
| BRIGHT MINDS BOOKS | 2023 |
| Bright Mind Books website programmer www.brightmindbooks.net | |
| GESTECH LIMITED | 2022 |
| Gestech website programmer www.gestechltd.com | |
| SHREE CUTCH SATSANG SWAMINARAYAN ACADEMY | 2022 |
| Website revamp assistant programmer www.scssacademy.sc.ke | |
| ROBERT WESLEY PROJECT | 2023 |
| Robert Wesley media website Main Programmer www.robertwesleymedia.co.ke | |
| JOSQUINE PROJECT | 2022 |

Josquine website revamp | Code Editor | www.josquine.co.ke

NIFUNZE PROJECT

Nifunze website | Code Editor | www.nifunze.co.ke

MUMAKANJAMA PROJECT

Website Design | Assistant programmer | www.mumakanjama.com

EDUCATION

DIPLOMA IN COMPUTER SCIENCE | Zetech University, Kiambu, Kenya

2017 - 2020

KCSE | Eastleigh High School, Nairobi, Kenya I managed to score a C - in my KCSE exams

2013 - 2016

KCPE | Heide Marie primary school Mathare 4A, Nairobi, Kenya I managed to score 284 marks in my final exams

2003 - 2010



Software engineer

+254 704 686 100 | willisopiyo@gmail.com | Nairobi, Kenya | | LinkedIn.com/in/willis-opiyo-7490492a3/

REFERENCES

Peter Kungu Kibathi

Director, Icon garden My director 0715015466

Peter.kibathi@joska.co.ke

Paul Kamau Kibathi

Director, Icon hotel 0723489904

Nelson Otieno

Director, Infinitech circle 0706577268

nelsonopiyo@gmail.com

Linda Machoka

Director, Talent soko africa 0720846420 linda.machoka@gmail.com

Robert Ocholi

Director, Robert Wesley media 0728153870

robertwesleymedia@gmail.com

Benson Mitigoa

Director, Mitigap

0791367912

Beauttah ingata

Director, Siron medical center 0714475607

ingatakbeauttah@icloud.com

